sproutsocial.com 2017-06-30

# Privacy Policy | Sprout Social

Sprout Social™ is committed to the privacy of our customers and their data. Our Privacy Policy applies to all users of Sprout Social™ websites and services, including but not limited to [www.sproutsocial.com](https://www.sproutsocial.com/), [www.getbambu.com](https://www.getbambu.com/), and [www.mustbepresent.com](https://www.mustbepresent.com/) (depending on your use, the “Site”). Depending on the Sprout Social service you are using, the Sprout Social Terms of Service or the service-specific Terms of Service (respectively, the “Terms”) is incorporated herein by reference. Our Terms of Service are available at: 

  * Sprout Social: <https://sproutsocial.com/terms>
  * Bambu: <https://getbambu.com/terms/>
  * Landscape: <https://sproutsocial.com/landscape/terms>
  * Mustbepresent: <https://mustbepresent.com/#!tos/>

All defined terms in the Privacy Policy have the same meaning as defined in the respective Terms. Sprout Social™ adheres to the following policies with regards to Your privacy. 

  1. ### Information Collected

When You enter the Site, We automatically collect information such as Your browser type and IP address. To offer You meaningful products and services and for the reasons set forth in this policy, We collect information about you, including Personally Identifiable Information, from the following sources: 

    * **Information We Collect Directly from You:** The type of information that we collect directly from you varies based on your interaction with our Site and our Services. We collect information directly from You when you complete an application or other forms on the Site and/or Software. We also collect information that you send us via any medium, including, but not limited to email, telephone, and social media interaction; or 
    * **Information We Collect Automatically:** If You use a mobile device platform to access the Services or communicate with Sprout Social™, information transmitted from Your mobile device; or 
    * **Information We Purchase:** Information purchased from third parties. 
    1. #### Registration

Sprout Social™ may request information from you during the registration process including, but not limited to: name, email address, company name and address, phone number, payment information, and/or social media profile information and authorization. Sprout Social™ may request other information from You during or after the registration process that Sprout Social™ uses to provide better and more customized services to Users. You acknowledge that this information is personal to You, and by creating an account on Sprout Social™, You may allow others, including Sprout Social™, to identify You and to allow Sprout Social™ to use Your information in accordance with the Terms. 

    2. #### Customer Service

We collect information when You interact with Sprout Social’s customer service in order to accurately categorize and respond to customer inquiries and investigate breaches of Our terms. 

    3. #### Using Third Party Services and Visiting Third Party Sites

Information You provide to third-party sites/websites through the Service are not within the control of Sprout Social™ and You provide such information at Your own risk. The terms and conditions of use and the privacy policies of those websites that You provide information to through the Service will govern their use of such information. Any information You share with a third-party site through the Service will be collected by Sprout Social™. Sprout Social™ will use such information in compliance with this Privacy Policy. 

    4. #### Information Collected Automatically

Use of Cookies. The Site may send a cookie to Your computer. Cookies allow us to recognize You as a user when You return to the Sprout Social™ website using the same computer and web browser and to monitor how you use the Site. We use cookies to identify which areas of Our site You have visited, so the next time You visit the site, those pages may be readily accessible. We also may use this information to better personalize the content that You see on the Site. We also use cookies to automatically capture activity on the Site, such as where You click, how You scroll through the Site, or what fields you enter text into (without seeing the actual text you enter). Most browser software can be set to reject Cookies. However, if You reject Our Cookies, certain functionality on the Site may not work correctly or at all. 

We may allow authorized third parties to place or recognize a unique cookie on Your browser. Sprout Social™ does not store unencrypted personally identifiable information in the cookies. 

If You send us notice that you object to our use of cookies, a “disagree” cookie will be stored in your browser and Sprout Social™ will not collect any session data. You can object to the collection and analysis of this anonymous data by emailing Your request to opt out to [privacy@sproutsocial.com](mailto:privacy@sproutsocial.com). 

    5. #### Web Beacons

Sprout Social™ also may use web beacons, pixels, anonymous ad network tags, and cookies to collect information about Your use of the Site and the websites of selected sponsors and advertisers, to collect anonymized, aggregated auditing, research and reporting for advertisers, and to collect data related to Your use of special promotions or newsletters. The information collected by Web Beacons also allows us to statistically monitor how many people open Our emails and for what purposes these actions are being taken. Our Web Beacons are not used to track Your activity outside of the Site or the websites of Our sponsors. However, because Your web browser requests advertisements and web beacons directly from ad network servers, these networks can view, edit or set their own cookies, just as if You had requested a web page from their site. If You are a non-registered Visitor to the Site, the only information We collect will be Non-Personal Information through the use of cookies or web beacons. 

    6. #### Log files, IP Addresses and information about Your computer and mobile device

Due to the communications standards on the internet, when You visit the Site We automatically receive the URL of the site from which You came and the site to which You are going when You leave Sprout Social’s Site. Sprout Social™ also receives the internet protocol (“IP”) address of Your computer (or the proxy server You use to access the World Wide Web), Your computer operating system and type of web browser You are using, email patterns, Your mobile device (including Your UDID or Vendor Identification) and mobile operating system (if You are accessing the Site using a mobile device), as well as the name of Your ISP or Your mobile carrier. Sprout Social™ may also receive location data passed to it from third-party services or GPS-enabled devices that You have enabled. Also, as described above in Section 1.D. Sprout Social™ receives information when You access third-party web pages through the Service. The link between Your IP address and Your personally identifiable information is not shared with third parties without Your permission, except as described in Section 8. ("When We May Disclose Your Information"), below. 

  2. ### Do-Not-Track

Currently, our systems do not recognize browser “do-not-track” requests. You may, however, disable certain tracking as discussed in this Privacy Policy (e.g., by disabling cookies, or using ‘private’ browsing modes). 

  3. ### Exemptions from Privacy Policy

Our Privacy Policy does not apply to any information You may send to Sprout Social™ by email or instant messaging programs (i.e. AOL, Yahoo, etc.), as email and instant messages are not recognized as secure communication forms. As such, We request that You do not send any information, which You consider private, to us by email or instant message. Furthermore, Our Privacy Policy does not apply to any information You post from Our Software to other websites (i.e. Twitter, Facebook, etc.), due to the public nature of such postings. 

  4. ### Use of Personally Identifiable Information

Sprout Social™ uses and/or intends to use Personally Identifiable Information to:

    * Operate and improve the Site;
    * Provide Users with the Service and other products and services that a User may request or that a User has expressed interest in;
    * Facilitate subscription processing, reviews and analysis;
    * Evaluate User interest and needs in order to improve the Service and make available other offers, products or services;
    * Evaluate the types of offers, products or services We make available to Users and potential Users;
    * Track use of the Services;
    * Provide customer support;
    * Communicate and provide additional information that may be of interest to Users through email or other means, such as special offers, announcements, and marketing materials;
    * Send You reminders, technical notices, updates, security alerts and support and administrative messages, service bulletins, or marketing;
    * Provide advertisements to You through email messages; and
    * Manage Our everyday business needs such as Site administration, forum management, fulfillment, analytics, fraud prevention, enforcement of Our corporate reporting obligations, Terms of Use or to comply with the law.
  5. ### Links/Postings to Other Sites

The Site and/or Software may contain links to other websites. Sprout Social™ is not responsible for the actions, practices, or content of such websites linked to or from the Site and/or Software. You understand that such websites may have their own legal documents to which You must agree to prior to using and that We have no control over these legal documents. As always, You understand that it is Your responsibility to verify Your legal use of a website as well as use of information from the website with the corresponding website owner 

  6. ### Market Research

Sprout Social™ may conduct online research surveys in order to gather feedback about the Site and opinions on important issues, through email invitations. When participating in a survey, We may ask You to submit Personally Identifiable Information. This Personally Identifiable Information is used for research purposes, and is not used for sales solicitations. Personally Identifiable Information collected through market research will be used only by Sprout Social™ and will not be given or sold to a third party without Your consent or as otherwise permitted by this Privacy Policy. 

  7. ### Use of Aggregate Data

Sprout Social™ may combine information You provide through the Site with information from other users to create aggregate data that may be disclosed to third parties. Aggregate information does not contain Your personal contact information. 

  8. ### When We May Disclose Your Information

We do not share Personally Identifiable Information with third parties for their own marketing purposes. We may disclose your information, including Personally Identifiable Information, for the following purposes: 

    1. We may share Personally Identifiable Information with Our contractors and service providers that perform services on Our behalf, including, but not limited to, operation of the Site technology, marketing services, and other related services. Access to Your Personally Identifiable Information by such contractors and service providers is limited to the information reasonably necessary for the contractor to perform its limited function for Sprout Social™. We also contractually require that such contractors and service providers: 1) protect the privacy of Your Personally Identifiable Information consistent with this Privacy Policy, and 2) not use or disclose Your Personally Identifiable Information for any purpose other than providing us with products and services as required by law. 
    2. We may share Personally Identifiable Information We collect, as permitted by law, with companies such as credit reporting agencies, or servicing and processing companies, or when required or advised to do so in response to a valid legal requirement to release this information such as a state or federal law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena, or court order; or (2) in special cases, such as in response to a physical threat to You or others, to protect property, or defend or assert legal rights, to defend ourselves in litigation. In the event that We are legally compelled to disclose Your Personally Identifiable information to a third party, We will attempt to notify You unless doing so would violate the law or court order. 
    3. Finally, Sprout Social™ may provide content and services to You through websites other than Our own. Sprout Social™ will not disclose Your Personally Identifiable Information to these 3rd party websites without Your consent, but You should be aware that any information You disclose on such sites is NOT subject to this Privacy Policy. 

If you request that we do not share Your personal data with a third-party, that request may result in your inability to use some or all of a Sprout Social™ service. If Your access to the Service is terminated based upon Your request that We do not share Your personal data with a third-party and that requests results in Your inability to use some or all of the Service, Your resulting inability to use the Service shall not be a basis for a refund or to avoid charges for the Service that You previously agreed to. 

  9. ### Access, Correction and Deletion of Personally Identifiable Data

You may request access to a report of the Personally Identifiable Information we maintain concerning Your use of the Service and you may request that the Personally Identifiable Information that we have collected and maintain be corrected or deleted. In order to make this request, please contact us at [privacy@sproutsocial.com](mailto:privacy@sproutsocial.com). Please be aware that if you request that we delete Your Personally Identifiable Information, You may no longer have access to the Service. If Your access to the Service is terminated based upon Your request that We delete Your Personally Identifiable Information, please be advised that Your resulting inability to use the Service shall not be a basis for a refund or to avoid charges for the Service that You previously agreed to. 

  10. ### Security Policy & User ID/Password

Our site utilizes various information security measures such as internet firewalls, an intrusion detection system, encrypted data transmission, and operating procedures that are designed to protect Your personal data, accounts, passwords, etc. You should protect Your user ID and password and NOT share it with anyone. If You believe Your user ID and password have been compromised and You have trouble changing your user ID/password on the Site or within the application, please contact Our technical support department ([support@sproutsocial.com](mailto:support@sproutsocial.com)). 

  11. ### CAN-SPAM Compliance Notice

We may send periodic promotional or informational emails to you. You may opt-out of such communications by following the opt-out instructions contained in the e-mail. Please note that it may take up to 10 business days for us to process opt-out requests. If you opt-out of receiving emails about recommendations or other information we think may interest you, we may still send you e-mails about your account or any Services you have requested or received from us. 

  12. ### Transfer of Ownership

If we are acquired by or merged with another company, if substantially all of our assets are transferred to another company, or as part of a bankruptcy proceeding, we may transfer the information we have collected from you to the other company. In any such transfer of information, Your user information would remain subject to the promises of Our then current Privacy Policy. 

  13. ### Notice to Residents of Countries outside of the United States of America

Sprout Social™ is headquartered in the United States of America. Personally Identifiable Information may be accessed by us or transferred to us in the United States or to Our affiliates, business partners, merchants, or service providers elsewhere in the world. By providing us with Personally Identifiable Information, You consent to this transfer in compliance with applicable law (in the case of data transfers from the EEA or Switzerland, these data transfers are covered under the Privacy Shield Framework). We will protect the privacy and security of Personally Identifiable Information according to Our Privacy Policy, regardless of where it is processed or stored. See below for additional information about our participation in the Privacy Shield program. 

  14. ### California Privacy Rights

Pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, residents of California can obtain certain information about the types of Personally Identifiable Information that companies with whom they have an established business relationship have shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year. In particular, the law provides that companies must inform consumers about the categories of Personally Identifiable Information that have been shared with third parties, the names and addresses of those third parties, and examples of the types of services or products marketed by those third parties. To request a copy of the information disclosure provided by Sprout Social™ pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, please contact us via email to [privacy@sproutsocial.com](mailto:privacy@sproutsocial.com). 

  15. ### EU - US Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss—US Privacy Shield Framework

Sprout Social complies with the EU—U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss—U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. Sprout Social has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to that its processing of Personally Identifiable Information from EU member countries, European Economic Area and Switzerland is in accordance with the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability (the “Principles”). If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Principles, the Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>. Sprout Social is subject to the investigatory and enforcement authority of the Federal Trade Commission. 

**Information We Process.** We collect, in accordance with the Privacy Shield principles, the categories of information described in Section 1 (Information Collected) above. We process this information for the purposes described in Sections 4 (Use of Personally Identifiable Information), 6 (Market Research) and 7 (Use of Aggregate Data). 

**Accessing Personally Identifiable Information.** The Privacy Shield Principles provide individuals located in the EU and Switzerland whose Personally Identifiable Information we process with the right to access their Personally Identifiable Information in order to review, correct, amend or delete information processed under the Principles. EU and Swiss individuals that are Sprout customers who would like to access their Personally Identifiable Information may contact us at [privacy@sproutsocial.com](mailto:privacy@sproutsocial.com). If your Personally Identifiable Information was provided to Sprout Social by one of our customers (where Sprout Social serves as a data processor), you should contact our customer directly to access your information. 

**Transfers to Third Parties.** As described in Section 8 (When We May Disclose Your Information) above, we transfer Personally Identifiable Information from the EU and Switzerland to our third party data processors. We contractually require third parties to which we transfer Personally Identifiable Information to provide the same level of protections as the Principles. Sprout Social remains responsible for the Personally Identifiable Information we receive and transfer under Privacy Shield. 

In accordance with our legal obligations, we also may transfer, subject to a lawful request, Personally Identifiable Information to public authorities in the US or the EU and Switzerland for law enforcement or national security purposes. 

**Contacting Us, Complaints and Dispute Resolution.** EU and Swiss individuals who have questions or complaints about how we process their Personally Identifiable Information may contact us at [privacy@sproutsocial.com](mailto:privacy@sproutsocial.com). We will work to resolve your issue and will respond within 45 days of receipt. 

Sprout Social has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-U.S. and Swiss—U.S Privacy Shield Principles to BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, a non-profit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States and operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgement of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/ for more information and to file a complaint. 

Individuals may also submit complaints through their local Data Protection Authority (DPA). We will work with the Department of Commerce to resolve any complaints forwarded by a DPA. Finally, if we are unable to resolve any complaints through any of the above methods, an EU or Swiss individual may invoke binding arbitration in accordance with the Privacy Shield Framework. 

  16. ### Privacy Complaints in Brazil

In circumstances in which Brazil law is controlling, We commit to resolve complaints about Your privacy and Our collection or use of Your Personally Identifiable Information. We have further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints to an independent dispute resolution mechanism. 

  17. ### Information and Other Rights, Contact

Upon written request, We would be happy to provide You with information as to whether – and if so, which – personal data We store in relation to You. Should Your personal data be incorrect, You may have this rectified immediately. Any such information or modification is free of charge. 

Moreover, You are entitled to revoke Your consent to use of data in the future, in whole or in part. Should You desire this, We will delete or block your relevant data; however, doing so may result in Your inability to use the Service in whole or in part. 

In order to assert such rights, please contact Sprout Social at [privacy@sproutsocial.com](mailto:privacy@sproutsocial.com). 

  18. ### Sprout’s Access to Your Account

You agree that Sprout Social™ can access Your account information in order to respond to Your service requests and/or as necessary, in Our sole discretion, to provide You with the Services. 

  19. ### Your Acceptance of This Privacy Policy

This is Our entire Privacy Policy and it supersedes any earlier version. You agree to it every time You use the Site and/or Software. 

If We make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, We will notify You by email or by posting a prominent notice on the Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage You to periodically review this page for the latest information on Our privacy practices. Your continued use of the Site or Service constitutes Your agreement to be bound by such changes to this Policy. Your only remedy, if You do not accept the terms of this Policy, is to discontinue use of the Site and Service. 

  20. ### Questions About This Privacy Policy

Should You have a privacy question about the Site and/or Software, please email Our customer service department ([support@sproutsocial.com](mailto:support@sproutsocial.com)). 

Effective: June 28, 2017
